Website * GitHub * LinkedIn

I am a product-focused senior engineer with 15 years of experience building and refining web applications. I specialize in modern frontend development with React and TypeScript, but I'm comfortable within the back-end as well, in particular in Python and NodeJS applications. I thrive on simplifying systems, speeding up iteration, and partnering with product and design to ship features that make a measurable impact.

Work Experience:

Idealist

Senior Frontend Engineer Dec 2018 - Present

- Led a number of technical projects, scoped with product and design, implementing frontend architecture in collaboration with a senior backend developer, and writing comprehensive unit and end-to-end tests.
- Reduced application build times from over a minute to under 5 seconds (~15× faster), vastly improving experience and
- Rebuilt the core search filters used across Jobs, Volunteering, and Events, driving a ~5–10% increase in filter usage while maintaining conversion rates to job views and applications.
- Drove architectural changes to make the codebase modular and extensible, decoupling search pages into reusable components. That flexibility enabled the embeddable search widget for partners, expanding product reach and creating a new revenue stream.
- Redesigned the job recommender engine to use filter scoring, resulting in a 38% lift in click-through rate and a 21.7% increase in submitted applications to recommended listings.
- Modernized legacy code by migrating Redux to lightweight state (Zustand), converting brittle class components into functional hooks, and rolling out a design system of composable UI primitives and theme manager, improving performance, accessibility, and developer velocity.
- Partnered with product and design to ship high-impact features including a block-based CMS with i18n support, an interactive international events map, and an automated content scheduler for multiple time zones.
- Raised engineering quality by mentoring peers in React, accessibility, testing practices, and performance profiling, and by championing maintainable, strongly-typed design patterns.

Condé Nast

Software Engineer 2 Feb 2017 - Nov 2018 | Software Engineer 1 Jan 2016 - Feb 2017

- Spearheaded frontend development of The New Yorker Caption Contest redesign, using GraphQL and React to rebuild a 14 year old application in a month. Average session duration on the new experience increased by 20%.
- Led a team of three to create the website for Clever, a millennial-focused offshoot of Architectural Digest. Clever led to a 759% increase in millennial traffic for the brand, and was nominated for a Webby for "best visual design — aesthetic".
- Contributed to the Webby-nominated Allure redesign, owning the product review page and global UI elements (header, navigation, footer).

Vattuo.net

Freelance Web Developer Sept 2014 - Jan 2016

Overhauled the Contra Costa County Guaranteed Ride Home Program, replacing a set of Google Forms with a Django/Backbone SPA to handle user submitted reimbursement requests and email notifications.

Citizen Engagement Lab

Web Developer and Digital Producer Mar 2012 - Sept 2014

Built over 20 websites for progressive political nonprofits, handling information architecture, full stack development, and management of outsourced design work.

Education: